Guide to the Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records, 1984-1997 AIS.1998.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records
1984-1997
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Peace Institute
AIS.1998.01
6.25 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
The Pittsburgh Peace Institute, which existed between 1984-1997, advocated nonviolent strategies to combat violence and oppression. The organization brought its message to the community and its youth, through classes, workshops, and school programs. The collection consists of board business, financial records, newsletters, publications, educational materials, and materials from its Making Choices program for youth.
Scope and Content Notes
The Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records date from 1984 to 1997 and document the activities of the organization which advocated methods nonviolence on an international, national, and local level. The collection is organized into three series: Administrative, Education and Outreach, and Audio and Visual Materials. Each series is organized alphabetically according to subject matter and chronologically within specific subjects. Where a significant amount of material exists, a separate section has been created within the series.
The Administrative series includes records pertaining to board business, committee activities, staff records, and financial records, including fundraising activities. The Education and Outreach series includes records pertaining to the PPI's abolitionist tour, book talk program, courses offered, Dealing With Prejudice program, workshops and the numerous publications the institute was involved in. A majority of the series is devoted to the Making Choices program, which were committed to teaching nonviolent problem solving to youth. The Audio and Visual Materials series includes photographs of program pilots and workshops and video featuring recordings of the Making Choices pilot program, and a documentary of the underground railroad in Western Massachusetts.
History
The Pittsburgh Peace Institute (PPI) was a private non-profit organization founded in 1984 in order to respond to the unavoidable increase in violence on a local, national, and international level. The institute was dedicated to providing community based education on the uses of nonviolence with an emphasis on programming for children and youth.
In order to combat adolescent violence and promote diversity, the institute developed two successful anti-violence programs for schools: Making Choices, developed for middle school students, and Dealing with Prejudice, for high school students.
The institute also offered a number of courses and workshops for adults that ranged from life skills, international issues, social justice and violence prevention. Additionally, the institute published The Peace Educator and The Subject is Nonviolence newsletters, as well as the books: Hammer of Justice: Molly Rush and Plowshares Eight; Simpleton Story: A Fairy Tale for the Nuclear Age; and Making Choices: A Program for Youth, which was used in conjunction with the Making Choices program in schools.
The PPI was originally located between the neighborhoods of Squirrel Hill and Shadyside on Wightman Ave., before moving in 1990 to the East Liberty Presbyterian Church. After almost 15 years of working with the community, the organization dissolved in 1997.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Janet Seltman in June 1999.
Related Material
Pennsylvania Peace Links Records, 1981-2004, AIS.2004.09, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Thomas Merton Center Records, 1971-2004, AIS.1982.19, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Previous Citation
Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records, 1984-1997, AIS.1998.01, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Social action; Associations; Education; Community education -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Political participation -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Social action -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Peace movements -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Pittsburgh Peace Institute
- Administrative, 1984-1997; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series documents the internal activities of the institute. The material dates from 1984-1997 and is arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically within the specific subjects. Much of the series is divided into sections in which a significant amount of material concerning a specific subject exists. The material includes administrative records, board member biographies, board business, committees business, and financial including fundraising activities.
  - Annual Education Programming Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Executive Director's Report, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board Biographies, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board Members
    - Artes, James, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Biggs, Dr. Shirley, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Brashear, Rev. Bob, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - DeBenedette, Abe, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Diallo, Diewo Barky, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ellis, Angele, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Evans, Dr. Fred, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Faltot, Rev. James, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Familoni, Pinkie, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fertman, Naomi, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ginsberg, Dr. Mark, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gould, Terri, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gore, Bob, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - May, Pat, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mariaskin, Lynn, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Norman, Liane, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Olson, Sallie, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Oursler, Barney, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Perry, Angala, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Rush, Molly, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Sable, Mike, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Salaam, Luqman Abdul, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Schaub, Tom, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Schoyer, Linda, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Segal, Ken, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Seltman, Janet, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Seltman, Rachel, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Seltman, Sarah, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Supowitz, Terri, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Taylor, Tommie Nell, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Vanda, Cynthia, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Wahrhaftig, Scilla, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Welbourne, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Wright, Mary Louise, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Young, Dr. Iris, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Board Business
    - Board Business, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Board Business, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Board Business, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Board Business, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Board Business, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Board Committees, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Board Handbook, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Board Handbook, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Board Handbook Sample, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Board List, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Board Meetings, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Board Meeting Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Board Nominating Committee, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Board Orientation, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Board Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Board Retreat, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Board Retreat, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Board Retreat, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Board Retreat, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Board Retreat, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - By-Laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Daily Activity Log, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Daily Phone/Mail Log, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Committees
    - Education Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Education Committee, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Education Committee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Education Committee, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Education Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Education Committee, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Education Committee, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Education Committee Former Members, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Executive Committee, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Executive Committee, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Personal Policies Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Publicity and Marketing Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Resource Development Committee, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Resource Development Committee, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Staff
    - Conolly- Manhardt, Ginny, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Executive Director Job Description, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Executive Director Search, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Intern File on Llewellyn, Marilyn, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Staff Job Descriptions, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Staff file for Siegal, Eleanor R., 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Staff Personnel Policies, Job Descriptions, and Letter of Agreement, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Staffing Plan, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Status Reports, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Financial
    - Accounting, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Annual Campaign, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Annual Campaign-Kim Klein Workshop, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Annual Campaign Letters, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Annual Campaign Volunteer Training, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Annual Campaign Contribution List, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Annual Campaign Materials, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Annual Campaign, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Auction, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Auction, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Auction, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Auction Information, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Auction, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Auction, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Budget, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Case Statement, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Contributions, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Donor Records, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Financial Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Financial Statements, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Financial Statements, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Financial Statements, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Financial Statements, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Financial Statements, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Fundraising for East Liberty Move, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Fundraising, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Fundraising Luncheon with Religious Orders, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Fundraising Correspondence List, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Grants Received, 1984-1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Benedum Foundation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bitner, H.M. Charitable Trust, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Max and Victoria Dreyfus Foundation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Pittsburgh Friends, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Hillman Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Holy Ghost Fathers, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Mellon Bank Foundation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - R.K. Mellon Foundation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Mobay-Heinz, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Pennsylvania Humanities Council, 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Patterson Charitable Fund, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - United Jewish Federation, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - United Way, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Weisbrod Foundation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Working Assets, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - 501(c)(3) tax information, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Education and Outreach, 1984-1997; II.
  This series dates from 1984-1997 and includes records pertaining to the various educational and community outreach programs that the Pittsburgh Peace Institute was involved in. The series is divided alphabetically into subjects and then chronologically within each subject. Much of the series is divided into sections in which a significant amount of material concerning a specific subject exists. Included are materials pertaining to the Abolitionist Tour, announcements and fliers, bibliographies of certain subjects of concern to the institute, book talk records, and the variety of courses and workshops offered. The series includes a significant amount of materials pertaining to the development and implementation of peace programs for schools, like "Making Choices," "Beyond Columbus," and "Dealing with Prejudice." Also included are the variety of publications the institute was involved in, for instance their newsletters: The Peace Educator and The Subject is Nonviolence, as well as the small and large publications the PPI produced, like The Hammer of Justice and Making Choices, used with the Making Choices program.
  - Abolitionist Tour Packet, undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Abolitionist Tour Press Coverage, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Abolitionist Tour Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Abolitionist Tour Funding, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Abolitionist Tour Program Planning, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Abolitionist Tour, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Abolitionist Tour Brochures and Posters, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Abolitionist Tour Prospect List and Letters, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Abolitionist Tour Miscellaneous Materials, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Abolitionist Tour for ITC, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Advocacy Training, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Advocacy Training Workshop, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alternatives to War Teacher's Guide, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Announcements and Fliers, 1984-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Announcements and Fliers, 1984-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Beyond Columbus, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Beyond Columbus Funding, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Beyond Columbus Student Reactions to Native American Speakers, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bibliography of Abolitionist Movement in PA compiled by John Burt, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography of Books on China, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bibliography of History of American Peace Movement, compiled by John Burt, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography for Fire in the East, Fire in the West course, compiled by John Burt, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bibliography for "First Amendment Rights" workshop, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bibliography of Peace and Violence Issues in Children's Books, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography to William Walker and United States, compiled by John Burt, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Books Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Book Talk Program Planning, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Book Talk Brochure Original, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Book Talk for The Measure of Our Success, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Book Talk Fliers, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Book Talk for Native American Testimony, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Book Talk for Al Gore's Earth in Balance, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Book Talk for Tawny Scrawny Lion, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Brochures, 1984-1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Children's Art and Related Items, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Consensus Statement, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Conflict Management Worksheets, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Conflict Management Workshop, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Conflict Resolution Program Plan, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Countdown to Eternity Docent Script, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Countdown to Eternity Projects, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Countdown to Eternity Program, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Countdown to Eternity Letters to Mrs. Martin Luther King, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Courses, Adult Programming Questionnaire, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Course Catalogues, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Course Description for "Role Models for Enduring Peace" and "Heroes for a Peaceful World", undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Course Fliers, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Course Inquiries, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Course Requests, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Course Rosters, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Course Schedules, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Course Schedules, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Course, Abolitionist Tour, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Course, Beyond Columbus, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Course, Civil Religion and America's War, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Course, Conflict Management, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Course, Conflict Resolution, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Course, The Crown of Columbus, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Course, Lighten Up, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Course, Parenting, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Course, Revolution and Change in Central America, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Cultural Diversity Workshop, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Creating Livable Schools Violence Prevention Workshop, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Creating Livable Schools Violence Prevention Workshop, November 13, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Creating Livable Schools Requests, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Prospectus, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Budget, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Draft, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Correspondence and Grants, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Curriculum, Outline, and Draft, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Observations and Evaluations, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Outline, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Workbook, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Draft of Part I, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Miscellaneous Papers, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Dealing With Prejudice Pilot Evaluation Report and Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Definition of Terms, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - First Strike Weapons By: Marie Norman, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Former Yugoslavia Talk, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Hammer of Justice, by: Liane Ellison Norman, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Hammer of Justice brochure, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Hammer of Justice Publicity, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Hammer of Justice Wholesale Terms, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Hammer of Justice balance due invoices from Baker and Taylor, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Hammer of Justice Orders, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Hammer of Justice discontinuation notice from Inland Book Company, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Hammer of Justice responses, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Hammer of Justice Requests, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - High School Curriculum plan, undated (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - In Pittsburgh article on PPI, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Living and Working Together Handbook, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - National Urban League "Seniors In Community Service" program, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Pittsburgh Middle and High Schools, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Making Choices Assessment Forms, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Making Choices Brochure, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Making Choices Curriculum Goals, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Making Choices Descriptions, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Making Choices Exercises, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Making Choices 9th Grade Activities, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Making Choices Media Coverage, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Making Choices Planning, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Making Choices Publicity, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Making Choices Role Models, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Making Choices Sample Poster, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Making Choices II Plans, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Making Choices Development, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Making Choices Student Letter to PPI, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Making Choices Survey, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Making Choices Teacher Training Session Sign Up, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Making Choices Use/Intent to Use, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Making Choices Miscellaneous Materials, 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Making Choices in USA Today, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Making Choices Progress Report, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Making Choices Book, by: Linda Schoyer, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Making Choices Copyright, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Making Choices Fundraising, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Making Choices Long Range Curriculum Plans, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Making Choices in Going Public journal, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Making Choices Responses and Letters of Support (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Making Choices Requests and Descriptions, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Making Choices Media Coverage, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Making Choices Curriculum Development Process, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Making Choices Teacher Evaluations, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Making Choices Prospectus, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Making Choices Intermediate Unit I, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Making Choices Presentations, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Making Choices Teacher Training Materials, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Making Choices Plans for Revised Edition, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Making Choices Revisions, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Making Choices Principal Letter, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Making Choices School Partnerships, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Making Choices Training Lesson Plans, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Making Choices Previous Contacts, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Making Choices Final Text, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Making Choices Formatted Text, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Making Choices plans with Brandegee, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Making Choices Evaluations, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Making Choices Evaluation Report, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Making Choices New Contacts, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Making Choices Not Contacted, No Response, or Not Interested, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Making Choices Summer Study Institute, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Making Choices Orders, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Making Choices Order Forms, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Making Choices 2nd Edition, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Making Choices Workshop, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Making Choices Student Picture, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Making Choices Costs, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Making Choices 2nd Edition Reviews, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Making Choices, Martin Luther King Jr. Unit Brochure and Cover, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Making Choices, Martin Luther King Jr. Unit Original Publication, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Making Choices, Martin Luther King Jr. Unit, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Making Choices, Martin Luther King Jr. Unit Chapter, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Making Choices, Martin Luther King Jr. General Letter, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Making Choices Schools, Allegheny Middle School, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Making Choices Schools, Americorps, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Making Choices Schools, Apollo Ridge School District, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Making Choices Schools, Arsenal Middle School, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Making Choices Schools, Baldwin High School, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Making Choices Schools, Canevin High School, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Making Choices Schools, East Allegheny Jr./Sr. High School, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Making Choices Schools, Ellis School, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 68)